<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Mobile Computing | Roberto Yus</title>
    <link>/tags/mobile-computing/</link>
      <atom:link href="/tags/mobile-computing/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Mobile Computing</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 01 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>/img/logo.png</url>
      <title>Mobile Computing</title>
      <link>/tags/mobile-computing/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Knowledge-Based Approach to Enhance Provision of Location-Based Services in Wireless Environments</title>
      <link>/publication/ieeeaccess-2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/publication/ieeeaccess-2020/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Android goes semantic</title>
      <link>/project/androidgoessemantic/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/project/androidgoessemantic/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The massive spread of mobile computing in our daily lives has attracted a huge community of mobile apps developers. These developers can take advantage of the benefits of semantic technologies (such as knowledge sharing and reusing, knowledge decoupling, etc.) to enhance their applications. Moreover, the use of semantic reasoners would enable them to create more intelligent applications capable of inferring logical consequences from the knowledge considered. However, using semantic APIs and reasoners on current Android-based devices is not problem-free and, currently, there are no remarkable efforts to enable mobile devices with semantic reasoning capabilities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In our work, we analyze whether the most popular current available DL reasoners can be used on Android-based devices. We evaluate the efforts needed to port them to the Android platform, taking into account its limitations, and present some tests to show the performance of these reasoners on current smartphones/tablets.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;useful-links-and-references&#34;&gt;Useful links and references&lt;/h4&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>FaceBlock</title>
      <link>/project/faceblock/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/project/faceblock/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Wearable technology is changing the human-computer interaction paradigm by improving the user experience. For example, eyewear technology, such as Google Glass, is opening a new world of possibilities. One of the best capabilities of such devices is that they allow spontaneous and effortless photo taking. Instead of pulling out your camera, turning it on, aiming, taking a picture and putting it away, Google Glass makes it as easy as saying “Okay Glass, take a picture”. However, their strength has also become controversial: people worry that their pictures could be taken without their knowledge or consent, violating their privacy. These privacy concerns are not new and have existed since camera technology became accessible to everyone. But, Google Glass makes it difficult to know when someone is taking a picture of you. Resorting to drastic measures, like banning their use in public places, is not a good solution.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We present FaceBlock, which protects the privacy rights of individuals by allowing them to choose whether or not to be included in pictures taken with Glass. Our approach allows a user’s mobile device to share privacy policies with nearby Glass devices using a P2P communication channel (our prototype uses Bluetooth). Along with the policy, users share information that helps identify them in a picture. When the Google Glass takes a picture
the system recognizes faces on it, checks policies it has received, and obscures faces as necessary.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;useful-links-and-references&#34;&gt;Useful links and references&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;FaceBlock in the news:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.nature.com/news/what-could-derail-the-wearables-revolution-1.18263&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Nature: &amp;ldquo;What could derail the wearables revolution?&amp;rdquo;, 2015&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://ebiquity.umbc.edu/blogger/2014/03/27/dont-be-a-glhole-use-faceblock/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;eBiquity UMBC: &amp;ldquo;Do not be a Gl***hole, use Face-Block.me!&amp;rdquo;, 2014&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MultiCAMBA</title>
      <link>/project/multicamba/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/project/multicamba/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;For a Technical Director (TD) in charge of a live broadcasting, selecting the best camera shots among the available video sources is a challenging task, even more now that the number of cameras (some of them mobile, or attached to moving objects) in the broadcasting of sport events is increasing. So, the TD needs to manage a great amount of continuously changing information to quickly select the camera whose view should be broadcasted. Besides, the better the decisions made by the TD, the more interesting the content for the audience. Therefore, the development of systems that could help the TD with the selection of camera views is demanded by broadcasting organizations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this project, we present the system MultiCAMBA that helps TDs in the live broadcasting task by allowing them to indicate in run-time their interest in certain kind of shots, and the system will show the cameras that are able to provide them. To achieve this task, the system manages location-dependent queries generated according to the interests of the TD. Moreover, to avoid the use of costly on line real-image processing techniques over the camera views, such real camera views are recreated in a 3D engine by using the information contained in a 3D model of the scenario. This model is updated continuously with real-time data retrieved from the real objects and cameras in the scenario. In this way, the system extracts high-level semantic features of 2D projections of the 3D reconstruction of the camera views.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;useful-links-and-references&#34;&gt;Useful links and references&lt;/h4&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SHERLOCK</title>
      <link>/project/sherlock/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/project/sherlock/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Nowadays people are exposed to huge amounts of information that are generated continuously; the ever-increasing use of mobile devices and their pervasiveness enable users to receive and create new contents almost anywhere. Currently, Location-Based Services (LBSs) are very popular, as they offer users customized information taking into account their current location. However, whereas users have access to a wide variety of information, current mobile apps, Web pages, and LBSs are designed for specific scenarios and goals. So, the information about the context they manage is not explicitly represented but embedded in their code. Moreover, developing services ad hoc for specific purposes leads to the fact that there exist thousands of them (even with the same purpose), and therefore it is difficult to choose the most suitable one. Therefore, currently it is a challenge to provide a common framework that allows to manage knowledge obtained from data sent by heterogeneous moving objects (textual data, multimedia data, sensor data, etc.). In addition, the challenge is even greater considering situations where the system must adapt itself to contexts where the knowledge changes dynamically and in which moving objects can use different underlying wireless technologies and positioning systems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We propose the system SHERLOCK, which offers a common framework with new functionalities for LBSs. As its namesake, the well-known Arthur Conan Doyle&amp;rsquo;s character, SHERLOCK uses abductive and deductive reasoning to infer information to answer user information requests (e.g., by providing interesting LBSs). Our system searches and shares up-to-date knowledge from nearby devices to relieve the user from knowing and managing such knowledge directly. Besides, the system guides the user in the process of selecting the service that best fits his/her needs in the given context. Finally, SHERLOCK processes user requests continuously to provide up-to-date answers in heterogeneous and dynamic contexts. Ontology reasoning and alignment methods are used to represent and manage, in a distributed way, the knowledge that describes moving and static objects (e.g., persons, vehicles, etc.) and interesting areas in a scenario. Moreover, the system uses mobile agent technology to carry the processing tasks wherever necessary in the dynamic underlying networks at any time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;useful-links-and-references&#34;&gt;Useful links and references&lt;/h4&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Semantic Management of Location-Based Services in Wireless Environments</title>
      <link>/publication/thesis-2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/publication/thesis-2016/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Continuous Processing of Real-Time Multimedia Requests Using Semantic Techniques</title>
      <link>/publication/momm-2015/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/publication/momm-2015/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cooperative Network of Mobile Agents to Remotely Process User Information Requests</title>
      <link>/publication/wi-poster-2015/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/publication/wi-poster-2015/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Semantic Reasoning on Mobile Devices: Do Androids Dream of Efficient Reasoners?</title>
      <link>/publication/jws-2015/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/publication/jws-2015/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Are Apps Going Semantic? A Systematic Review of Semantic Mobile Applications</title>
      <link>/publication/modest-2015/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Oct 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/publication/modest-2015/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building a Mobile Applications Knowledge Base for the Linked Data Cloud</title>
      <link>/publication/modest2-2015/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Oct 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/publication/modest2-2015/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mobile Endpoints: Accessing Dynamic Information from Mobile Devices</title>
      <link>/publication/iswc-2015/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Oct 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/publication/iswc-2015/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mobipedia: Mobile Applications Linked Data</title>
      <link>/publication/iswc2-2015/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Oct 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/publication/iswc2-2015/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 4: Emerging Semantic-Based Applications</title>
      <link>/publication/workman-2015/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Aug 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/publication/workman-2015/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The OWL Reasoner Evaluation Goes Mobile</title>
      <link>/publication/ore-2015/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/publication/ore-2015/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Emergency Management Using SHERLOCK</title>
      <link>/publication/mobisys-2015/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 May 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/publication/mobisys-2015/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SHERLOCK: Semantic Management of Location-Based Services in Wireless Environments</title>
      <link>/publication/pmc-2014/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/publication/pmc-2014/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Flexible Access to Services in Smart Cities: Let SHERLOCK Advise Modern Citizens</title>
      <link>/publication/ercim-2014/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Nov 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/publication/ercim-2014/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Semantic Context-Aware Privacy Model for FaceBlock</title>
      <link>/publication/privon2-2014/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/publication/privon2-2014/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rafiki: A Semantic and Collaborative Approach to Community Health-care in Underserved Areas</title>
      <link>/publication/collaboratecom-2014/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/publication/collaboratecom-2014/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Semantics for Privacy and Shared Context</title>
      <link>/publication/privon-2014/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/publication/privon-2014/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Android Went Semantic: Time for Evaluation</title>
      <link>/publication/ore-2014/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/publication/ore-2014/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>FaceBlock: Privacy-Aware Pictures for Google Glass</title>
      <link>/publication/mobisys-2014/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jun 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/publication/mobisys-2014/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SHERLOCK: A System for Location-Based Services in Wireless Environments Using Semantics</title>
      <link>/publication/www-13/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/publication/www-13/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Android goes Semantic: DL Reasoners on Smartphones</title>
      <link>/publication/ore-2013/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/publication/ore-2013/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Semantic Management of Moving Objects with SHERLOCK</title>
      <link>/publication/frdinmovement-2013/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/publication/frdinmovement-2013/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Semantic-Based Query Processing on Moving Objects</title>
      <link>/publication/frdinmovement-2012/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/publication/frdinmovement-2012/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
