<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Privacy | Roberto Yus</title>
    <link>/tags/privacy/</link>
      <atom:link href="/tags/privacy/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Privacy</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 17 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>/img/logo.png</url>
      <title>Privacy</title>
      <link>/tags/privacy/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>BL(u)E CRAB: A User-Centric Framework for Identifying Suspicious Bluetooth Trackers</title>
      <link>/publication/percom-demo-bluecrab-2025/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/publication/percom-demo-bluecrab-2025/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>LOADS: LiDAR-based Privacy-Preserving Queue Monitoring and Analysis</title>
      <link>/publication/percom-demo-loads-2025/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/publication/percom-demo-loads-2025/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Your Smart Home Exchanged 3M Messages: Defining and Analyzing Smart Device Passive Mode</title>
      <link>/publication/percom-2025/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/publication/percom-2025/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GenAIPABench: A Benchmark for Generative AI-based Privacy Assistants</title>
      <link>/publication/popets-2024/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/publication/popets-2024/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PrivacyLens</title>
      <link>/project/privacylens/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/project/privacylens/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;PrivacyLens is a novel framework devised to automatically collect, analyze, and publish privacy policies of smart IoT devices, responding to the growing concerns over user privacy as smart devices become increasingly integrated into daily lives. Despite the existence of privacy policies, a significant challenge arises as they are often overlooked or misunderstood by users, hence the need for an automated analysis to provide clearer insights to users and other stakeholders. Unlike previous works, this project pivots towards addressing the gap in privacy policies specific to smart devices which present unique challenges in collection and analysis due to their dispersed nature across various manufacturers and e-commerce platforms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The PrivacyLens framework operates in three core stages; Collection, Analysis, and Publication. Initially, it crawls prominent e-commerce sites for smart IoT devices, extracting metadata and privacy policies, while also utilizing the Wayback Machine to garner historical privacy policies for longitudinal analysis. Following the collection, the framework employs Natural Language Processing (NLP) and Machine Learning (ML) techniques to dissect these policies, aiming to deduce features like overall quality, readability, and ambiguity among others. The final stage sees the publishing of this analyzed data on a dedicated website, updated monthly to provide users, policy authors, and regulators a robust, updated resource to understand and compare privacy practices across a multitude of smart devices. As of the submission, PrivacyLens has successfully amassed and analyzed over 1,200 privacy policies for 7,300 smart devices, presenting a significant stride towards fostering transparency and informed decision-making in the realm of smart device privacy. Through PrivacyLens, stakeholders varying from ordinary consumers to data protection regulators are equipped with a powerful tool to understand and navigate the privacy landscape of IoT devices, marking a crucial step towards creating a more responsible and transparent digital ecosystem.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>International Mutual Recognition: A Description of Trust Services in US, UK, EU and JP and the Testbed “Hakoniwa”</title>
      <link>/publication/secrypt-2023/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/publication/secrypt-2023/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>One-Shot Federated Group Collaborative Filtering</title>
      <link>/publication/icmla-2022/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/publication/icmla-2022/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Privacy-Enabled Platform for COVID-19 Applications</title>
      <link>/publication/sensys-demo-2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/publication/sensys-demo-2020/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Transitioning from testbeds to ships: an experience study in deploying the TIPPERS Internet of Things platform to the US Navy</title>
      <link>/publication/jdms-2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/publication/jdms-2020/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sieve: A Middleware Approach to Scalable Access Control for Database Management Systems</title>
      <link>/publication/vldb-2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/publication/vldb-2020/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>FaceBlock</title>
      <link>/project/faceblock/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/project/faceblock/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Wearable technology is changing the human-computer interaction paradigm by improving the user experience. For example, eyewear technology, such as Google Glass, is opening a new world of possibilities. One of the best capabilities of such devices is that they allow spontaneous and effortless photo taking. Instead of pulling out your camera, turning it on, aiming, taking a picture and putting it away, Google Glass makes it as easy as saying “Okay Glass, take a picture”. However, their strength has also become controversial: people worry that their pictures could be taken without their knowledge or consent, violating their privacy. These privacy concerns are not new and have existed since camera technology became accessible to everyone. But, Google Glass makes it difficult to know when someone is taking a picture of you. Resorting to drastic measures, like banning their use in public places, is not a good solution.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We present FaceBlock, which protects the privacy rights of individuals by allowing them to choose whether or not to be included in pictures taken with Glass. Our approach allows a user’s mobile device to share privacy policies with nearby Glass devices using a P2P communication channel (our prototype uses Bluetooth). Along with the policy, users share information that helps identify them in a picture. When the Google Glass takes a picture
the system recognizes faces on it, checks policies it has received, and obscures faces as necessary.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;useful-links-and-references&#34;&gt;Useful links and references&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;FaceBlock in the news:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.nature.com/news/what-could-derail-the-wearables-revolution-1.18263&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Nature: &amp;ldquo;What could derail the wearables revolution?&amp;rdquo;, 2015&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://ebiquity.umbc.edu/blogger/2014/03/27/dont-be-a-glhole-use-faceblock/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;eBiquity UMBC: &amp;ldquo;Do not be a Gl***hole, use Face-Block.me!&amp;rdquo;, 2014&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SemIoTic</title>
      <link>/project/semiotic/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/project/semiotic/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;SemIoTic is a middleware framework for IoT smart spaces that provides application developers and end-users with a semantic domain-relevant view of a smart space 
while hiding the complexity of having to deal with/understand lower-level information generated by sensors and actuators. SemIoTic uses a metamodel based on the popular 
SOSA/SSN ontology with some extensions to represent relationships between the low-level IoT devices&#39; world (i.e., devices, observations) and semantic concepts 
(i.e., observable attributes of users and spaces). It supports a language where users can express their action requirements (i.e., requests for sensor data, commands 
for actuators, and privacy preferences) in terms of user-friendly high-level concepts. We present an ontology-based algorithmic approach to translate user-defined actions 
into sensor/actuators commands. Finally, our end-to-end approach includes a cross-layer solution to provide interoperability with diverse IoT devices and their data exchange protocols.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Several instances of SemIoTic have been deployed and used in IoT spaces. At the Donald Bren Hall building of UC Irvine, building occupants 
have access to Concierge and Building Analytics smart applications and building administrators have access to a Contact Tracing Application to help combat the spread of COVID-19.
Also, SemIoTic has been deployed inside a navy ship from the Naval Information Warfare Center (NIWC) 
in the context of the Trident Warrior exercise 2019/2020. SemIoTic enabled testing of applications such as occupancy analysis in multiple 
regions of the ship.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;useful-links-and-references&#34;&gt;Useful links and references&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;SemIoTic is developed as part of the &lt;a href=&#34;http://tippers.ics.uci.edu&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;TIPPERS&lt;/a&gt; (Testbed for IoT-based Privacy-Preserving PERvasive Spaces) DARPA research project.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TIPPERS</title>
      <link>/project/tippers/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/project/tippers/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;TIPPERS is an IoT data management middleware that manages IoT smart spaces by collecting sensor data, inferring semantically meaningful information from it, and offering such inferences to developers to create smart applications. Sensor data collection, processing, and sharing leads to potential violations of people’s privacy given the sensitivity of the data and the inferences that can be extracted from it. TIPPERS integrates different Privacy Enhancing Technologies (e.g., policy-based access control, differential privacy, secure computing, etc.) to deal with privacy issues in IoT data management.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;TIPPERS has been deployed in several IoT smart spaces. The main deployment is at the UC Irvine campus where it handles IoT data from more than 20 buildings. Based on such data (including connectivity logs from WiFi APs, HVAC data, video footage, etc.) TIPPERS generates inferences such as location of people and occupancy of spaces. We have developed several smart applications which use those inferences to offer personalized services to the campus inhabitants. In particular, we have recently developed COVID-19 regulation monitoring tools to assess the adherence of the community to occupancy regulations. TIPPERS has also been successfully deployed in two US Navy ships as part of the Trident Warrior 2019 and 2020 excersice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;useful-links-and-references&#34;&gt;Useful links and references&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;TIPPERS is funded by DARPA as part of the Brandeis program.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;TIPPERS in the news:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.washingtonpost.com/news/powerpost/paloma/the-technology-202/2020/07/10/the-technology-202-tech-to-contain-coronavirus-on-college-campuses-spark-fresh-privacy-concerns/5f077b4a88e0fa7b44f716e8/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;The Washington Post: &amp;ldquo;The Technology 202: Tech to contain coronavirus on college campuses sparks fresh privacy concerns&amp;rdquo;, 2020&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://healthitanalytics.com/news/uci-uses-campus-wi-fi-to-test-covid-19-contact-tracing-app&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Health IT Analytics: &amp;ldquo;UCI Uses Campus Wi-Fi to Test COVID-19 Contact Tracing App&amp;rdquo;, 2020&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ics.uci.edu/community/news/view_news?id=1803&amp;amp;fbclid=IwAR1Ep27zST5KYJKC1a6GBB83tnEfLRvsgQlTossIOMkiIeGjVZBXJFjYua8&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;UCI news: &amp;ldquo;Test bed for COVID-19 contact tracing system&amp;rdquo;, 2020&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.dvidshub.net/news/374318/navwar-trident-warrior-team-assesses-new-tracking-technology-covid-19-mitigation&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Defense Visual Information Distribution Service: &amp;ldquo;NAVWAR Assesses New Tracking Technology for COVID-19 Mitigation&amp;rdquo;, 2020&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.militarynews.com/news/navy-tests-experimental-technology-at-trident-warrior/article_55623050-dedf-11e9-8e21-4f20e90f315a.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Military News: &amp;ldquo;Navy tests experimental technology at Trident Warrior 2019&amp;rdquo;, 2019&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.cs.uci.edu/iot-hackathon-apps-coming-soon/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;UCI CS News: &amp;ldquo;IoT Hackathon Apps Coming Soon&amp;rdquo;, 2018&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.cs.uci.edu/ics-launches-iot-hackathon-to-discover-student-talent-who-can-develop-a-uci-smart-campus&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;UCI CS News: &amp;ldquo;ICS launches IoT Hackathon to discover student talent who can develop a UCI ‘smart’ campus&amp;rdquo;, 2017&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IoT-Detective: Analyzing IoT Data Under Differential Privacy</title>
      <link>/publication/sigmod-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/publication/sigmod-2018/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Trustworthy Privacy Policy Translation in Untrusted IoT Environments</title>
      <link>/publication/iotbds-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/publication/iotbds-2018/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Towards Privacy-Aware Smart Buildings: Capturing, Communicating, and Enforcing Privacy Policies and Preferences</title>
      <link>/publication/iotca-2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/publication/iotca-2017/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Semantic Context-Aware Privacy Model for FaceBlock</title>
      <link>/publication/privon2-2014/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/publication/privon2-2014/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>FaceBlock: Privacy-Aware Pictures for Google Glass</title>
      <link>/publication/mobisys-2014/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jun 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/publication/mobisys-2014/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
