<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Internet of Things | Roberto Yus</title>
    <link>/tags/internet-of-things/</link>
      <atom:link href="/tags/internet-of-things/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Internet of Things</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>/img/logo.png</url>
      <title>Internet of Things</title>
      <link>/tags/internet-of-things/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>LOCATER: Cleaning WiFi Connectivity Datasets for Semantic Localization</title>
      <link>/publication/vldb3-2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/publication/vldb3-2020/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Privacy-Enabled Platform for COVID-19 Applications</title>
      <link>/publication/sensys-demo-2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/publication/sensys-demo-2020/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Transitioning from testbeds to ships: an experience study in deploying the TIPPERS Internet of Things platform to the US Navy</title>
      <link>/publication/jdms-2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/publication/jdms-2020/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SmartBench: A Benchmark For Data Management In Smart Spaces</title>
      <link>/publication/vldb2-2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/publication/vldb2-2020/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Abstracting Interactions with IoT Devices Towards a Semantic Vision of Smart Spaces</title>
      <link>/publication/buildsys-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/publication/buildsys-2019/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SemIoTic: Bridging the Semantic Gap in IoT Spaces</title>
      <link>/publication/buildsys-demo-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/publication/buildsys-demo-2019/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SemIoTic</title>
      <link>/project/semiotic/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/project/semiotic/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;SemIoTic is a middleware framework for IoT smart spaces that provides application developers and end-users with a semantic domain-relevant view of a smart space 
while hiding the complexity of having to deal with/understand lower-level information generated by sensors and actuators. SemIoTic uses a metamodel based on the popular 
SOSA/SSN ontology with some extensions to represent relationships between the low-level IoT devices&#39; world (i.e., devices, observations) and semantic concepts 
(i.e., observable attributes of users and spaces). It supports a language where users can express their action requirements (i.e., requests for sensor data, commands 
for actuators, and privacy preferences) in terms of user-friendly high-level concepts. We present an ontology-based algorithmic approach to translate user-defined actions 
into sensor/actuators commands. Finally, our end-to-end approach includes a cross-layer solution to provide interoperability with diverse IoT devices and their data exchange protocols.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Several instances of SemIoTic have been deployed and used in IoT spaces. At the Donald Bren Hall building of UC Irvine, building occupants 
have access to Concierge and Building Analytics smart applications and building administrators have access to a Contact Tracing Application to help combat the spread of COVID-19.
Also, SemIoTic has been deployed inside a navy ship from the Naval Information Warfare Center (NIWC) 
in the context of the Trident Warrior exercise 2019/2020. SemIoTic enabled testing of applications such as occupancy analysis in multiple 
regions of the ship.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;useful-links-and-references&#34;&gt;Useful links and references&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;SemIoTic is developed as part of the &lt;a href=&#34;http://tippers.ics.uci.edu&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;TIPPERS&lt;/a&gt; (Testbed for IoT-based Privacy-Preserving PERvasive Spaces) DARPA research project.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TIPPERS</title>
      <link>/project/tippers/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/project/tippers/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;TIPPERS is an IoT data management middleware that manages IoT smart spaces by collecting sensor data, inferring semantically meaningful information from it, and offering such inferences to developers to create smart applications. Sensor data collection, processing, and sharing leads to potential violations of people’s privacy given the sensitivity of the data and the inferences that can be extracted from it. TIPPERS integrates different Privacy Enhancing Technologies (e.g., policy-based access control, differential privacy, secure computing, etc.) to deal with privacy issues in IoT data management.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;TIPPERS has been deployed in several IoT smart spaces. The main deployment is at the UC Irvine campus where it handles IoT data from more than 20 buildings. Based on such data (including connectivity logs from WiFi APs, HVAC data, video footage, etc.) TIPPERS generates inferences such as location of people and occupancy of spaces. We have developed several smart applications which use those inferences to offer personalized services to the campus inhabitants. In particular, we have recently developed COVID-19 regulation monitoring tools to assess the adherence of the community to occupancy regulations. TIPPERS has also been successfully deployed in two US Navy ships as part of the Trident Warrior 2019 and 2020 excersice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;useful-links-and-references&#34;&gt;Useful links and references&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;TIPPERS is funded by DARPA as part of the Brandeis program.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;TIPPERS in the news:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.washingtonpost.com/news/powerpost/paloma/the-technology-202/2020/07/10/the-technology-202-tech-to-contain-coronavirus-on-college-campuses-spark-fresh-privacy-concerns/5f077b4a88e0fa7b44f716e8/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;The Washington Post: &amp;ldquo;The Technology 202: Tech to contain coronavirus on college campuses sparks fresh privacy concerns&amp;rdquo;, 2020&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://healthitanalytics.com/news/uci-uses-campus-wi-fi-to-test-covid-19-contact-tracing-app&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Health IT Analytics: &amp;ldquo;UCI Uses Campus Wi-Fi to Test COVID-19 Contact Tracing App&amp;rdquo;, 2020&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ics.uci.edu/community/news/view_news?id=1803&amp;amp;fbclid=IwAR1Ep27zST5KYJKC1a6GBB83tnEfLRvsgQlTossIOMkiIeGjVZBXJFjYua8&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;UCI news: &amp;ldquo;Test bed for COVID-19 contact tracing system&amp;rdquo;, 2020&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.dvidshub.net/news/374318/navwar-trident-warrior-team-assesses-new-tracking-technology-covid-19-mitigation&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Defense Visual Information Distribution Service: &amp;ldquo;NAVWAR Assesses New Tracking Technology for COVID-19 Mitigation&amp;rdquo;, 2020&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.militarynews.com/news/navy-tests-experimental-technology-at-trident-warrior/article_55623050-dedf-11e9-8e21-4f20e90f315a.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Military News: &amp;ldquo;Navy tests experimental technology at Trident Warrior 2019&amp;rdquo;, 2019&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.cs.uci.edu/iot-hackathon-apps-coming-soon/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;UCI CS News: &amp;ldquo;IoT Hackathon Apps Coming Soon&amp;rdquo;, 2018&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.cs.uci.edu/ics-launches-iot-hackathon-to-discover-student-talent-who-can-develop-a-uci-smart-campus&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;UCI CS News: &amp;ldquo;ICS launches IoT Hackathon to discover student talent who can develop a UCI ‘smart’ campus&amp;rdquo;, 2017&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IoT-Detective: Analyzing IoT Data Under Differential Privacy</title>
      <link>/publication/sigmod-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/publication/sigmod-2018/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Trustworthy Privacy Policy Translation in Untrusted IoT Environments</title>
      <link>/publication/iotbds-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/publication/iotbds-2018/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exploring fairness in participatory thermal comfort control in smart buildings</title>
      <link>/publication/buildsys-2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/publication/buildsys-2017/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Towards Privacy-Aware Smart Buildings: Capturing, Communicating, and Enforcing Privacy Policies and Preferences</title>
      <link>/publication/iotca-2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/publication/iotca-2017/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
